Peter Boyle

Boyle.Peter614@gmail.com Ph: 973-650-0479

Github: https://github.com/boylepeter
About Me: https://boylepeter.github.io/businesscard/
Portfolio: https://boylepeter.github.io/porty/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peterjosephboyle/

Summary

Experienced Full Stack Web Developer with 3+ years of experience and US Navy Special Operations Veteran. After a decade and a half in military and civilian medicine, an illness involving temporary paralysis caused a transition in career paths. Now accomplished in both backend and frontend development with advanced proficiency in big data and fin-tech development, and having participated in the sunrise of three platforms, lead development on two enterprise level projects while also managing one of those, continuing to evolve and progress as an engineer.

Technical Skills

Languages/Libraries: HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS, JavaScript ES6, React, Redux, Express, Node, JQuery

Technologies: Git, Heroku, API, Restful API, JSON, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Terminal, Bash, AJAX, Mongoose, Sequelize, CLI

Database: MySQL, SQL, NoSQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Atlas & Compass, Workbench, Postman

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Education

University of North Carolina Charlotte:

10/2020-01/2021

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp: Coding Certificate

Graduated and excelled in a full time immersive Full Stack Web Development program. Explored and built skill and ability in both front and back-end development

Utilized languages such as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Mongo, Express, and React.

Professional Experience

• Staff Consultant Developer, Stripe Practice : Myers Holum International

7/2022-Present

Entrusted with furnishing consultation and development services for clients seeking clean, reliable, and scalable Stripe integrations for management of payment processing, reporting, financial security and more. Earned the title of "Stripe Practice Employee of the Quarter" in my first quarter.

Lead development efforts on two projects. One project largely focused on consultation aimed at optimizing payment flows, improving operating speeds, and minimizing costs to the client. The second was a fully custom integration, for which I also functioned as Project Manager, capable of processing 30,000+ invoices daily via batch payments, a custom UI and scalable payment solution for daily manual payments, as well as managing reporting for both methodologies.

Senior Software Engineer, DevOps : Wells Fargo

11/2021-7/2022

Provided technical support and maintained the configuration management system data for business applications in development, test, and production.

Conduct oversight and manage the administration, maintenance, and security of applications in production as well as in lower lanes.

Participated in the sunrise of multiple core applications within the Wells Fargo Data Solutions and Services footprint with a reach to all 70m+ customers.

• Freelance Software Developer:

04/2021-10/2021

Inquiring Minds | inquiringminds-II.com

An Ecommerce app for a retailer of educational tools aimed at keeping seniors active mentally. Javascript, API

Promotion Chiropractic

Physical therapy app for a doctor's practice focused on expanding patient access to physical rehab protocols including stretching and exercises.

React, MySQL, Express, Node

• Paramedic: Fort Mill Rescue, Century Ambulance, Liberty Ambulance

09/2016-03/2019

Led an ambulance crew in caring for advanced life support 911 patients. Oversaw and controlled all scenes within an area of responsibility. This ranges from orchestrating a two-person team to multiple ambulance and fire crews all working under the purview of the paramedic in charge.

Trained EMTs and Fire Dept personnel in ongoing medical education as well as new and advanced techniques. Led and participated in Scrum style meetings/planning.

Controlled all invasive, drug, and advanced care of patients, as well as oversight of EMT, and legal responsibility for the ambulance, crew, and patient. Conducted these tasks without incident.

Surgical Assistant: UF Health Jacksonville

01/2014-08/2016

Headed evaluation and treatment plans of both surgical and non-operative patients within the surgical suite. Specialized in traumatic and orthopedic patients who require immediate diagnosis and treatment. Advanced and increased surgical abilities within the department by becoming the only assistant well educated and trained in all surgical procedures run in clinic. Oversaw integration of and liaised with contractors in the care, troubleshooting, maintenance, and operation of all new technology and tools within the suite.

Interim Positions after leaving the military

2012-01/2014

Military Experience

USN: Reconnaissance Corpsman

2008-2012

Served as a member of 1st Recon Bn, Battalion Landing Team 3/1, and the 11th Marine Expeditionary Unit.

Assumed the role of sole medical provider for a reconnaissance and surveillance platoon, functioning as both a team member, as well as a medical asset.

Created long standing medical standard operating procedures including medevac procedures and techniques for extrication and movement still in practice today.

Trained in reconnaissance and surveillance as well as direct action and interdiction. Medical follow on training in advanced trauma, ER trauma, high altitude and mountain medicine, diving and hyperbaric medicine.